# JOSHUA PALAMUTTAM

https://github.com/joshpal<br/>97  $\diamond$ https://www.Joshua Palamuttam.com San Jose, CA 95138

 $(408) \cdot 841 \cdot 6194 \diamond joshpal97@gmail.com$ 

## SUMMARY

A highly-motivated computer professional, who graduated with a Computer Science degree from Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology '19, with the enthusiasm to accept, and individually solve new challenges. The positions I have been in have given me hands-on work experience working on application design, development, and quality assurance using agile practices, and writing clean code.

## EDUCATION

# Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology

2015 - 2019

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Counterpart

May 2020 - Present

Software Engineer, Fishers, IN

- · Independently architect the React frontend for a higher education financial funding tool for the Indiana state government
- · Assist in the creation of a community service engagement tool for startup Donaide, using .Net MVC
- · Develop new features, and maintain a custom internal task management software for Keramida, and a custom software selling environmental reports, for ISRI using .Net MVC

# Kaiser Permanente Genetics

February 2020 - May 2020

Junior Dot Net Analyst, San Jose, CA

Research and development for .Net Core MVC, with SQL applications used by the Genetics DepartmentGather requirements while developing and supporting applications such as an Assay Management tool Occasionally created autonomous Batch Files, or Excel VBA scripts to aid Lab Technicians in their duties

 $\mathbf{DMI}$ 

May 2019 - February 2020

Software Engineer, Indianapolis. IN

- · Develop a POC to optimize lot operations at a car auction site, using Angular, Node.js, AWS serverless, SQL
- · Assisted in the development of a physics engine to simulate a transmission, for Allison Transmission, proprietary math was done using C++, passed to a Angular, .Net Core, SQL stack, using EF Core
- · Built Microsoft Teams Chat bot for DMI, using LUIS an Azure Cognitive Service (NLP)
- · All projects used Azure Devops to adhere to SAFe agile practices, such as CI/CD, unit and integration testing

## **PROJECTS**

# Full stack portfolio website, (React, Gatsby, GCP, GraphQl)

Spring 2020

- · The website can be found at this link: https://www.joshuapalamuttam.com or github
- · Developed and Integrated a GCP Postgres SQL instance for the back end
- · Deployed front end through Strapi, and built with Gatsby, and React, hosted through Netlify
- · All API requests, are received through Graphql, and not a regular REST API

# Compile.io (Angular, Spring Boot, MongoDb, Docker)

2018-2019

- · Developed a scalable website that automatically grades student submitted code
- · Code was submitted through the Angular front-end, taken to our Java Spring backend, processed in a docker container, and stored in MongoDB.
- · Gathered requirements from professors, and wrote documentation that can be viewed in my github

## Stock Market Analysis through Twitter (Python)

Spring 2019

- · The purpose of this project was to figure out how a companys twitter handle and companys CEO twitter handle affected the companys stock
- · Performed Latent Semantic Analysis on tweets for those twitter handles
- · Pre-processed data by removing stop words, duplicate tweets, and special characters

## SKILLS

Programming Languages JavaScript, Typescript, C#, Java, SQL, HTML, CSS, Python

Frameworks
Angular, React, Node.js, Spring, .Net Core, Entity Framework Core, .Net
Tools
AWS, Azure, GCP, Docker, Git, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, GraphQl

Certifications AWS Cloud Practitioner, SAFe 4.6